http://www.arv.org.au/about-us/privacy-policy/

Back
Anglicare Family Relationship Centre Celebrates 10 Years in Nowra
Anglicare’s Response to Coronavirus (COVID-19)
New Aged Care Home Opens at the Ponds
Cafe course serves up a better future for Mt Druitt students
Bag a bargain at Anglicare’s Latest Narellan Shop
Coogee Cafe Celebrates Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Culture
Latest research shows alterations in the blood may detect the onset of Alzheimer’s disease
New Reconciliation Action Plan for 160 year old organisation
New program opens in Parramatta for refugee children
Castle Hill graduate program trains new nurses to care for the aged
Small grants available for Refugee Ministries
High demand for quality retirement living units in the Hills
New Program Opens in Bankstown for Refugee Children
Join “Beating the Blues” Walk at Prince Alfred Park to Support Better Mental Health
Sydney’s Housing Crisis Pushing Frail Aged Into Homelessness
Sydney Anglican Archbishop Commissions NSW First Female Police Chaplain
Anglicare Launches Wills Day in Summer Hill
Anglicare's Mobile Community Pantry Opens in Granville
Language No Barrier to Friendship at Ryde ESL Class
Outstanding Achievers at the Australian Charity Awards
Campbelltown Low Income Families to Slash Electricity Bills Thanks to New Program
Supporting Dads at Anglicare Mt Druitt
Anglicare Urges Penrith Shoppers to do Good by Looking Great
Anglicare Low Cost Food Van Drives Dollar Further for Low Income Families
More Frail Aged on the Verge of Eviction in the Eastern Suburbs
Anglicare's Mobile Community Pantry Opens in Liverpool
CEO Appointed to Steer Anglicare's New Course
Anglicare Name Stands the Test of Time
Testing times for integration in Australia
Anglicare Elizabeth Lodge First in Australia to be Montessori Accredited
Anglicare low cost food van drives dollar further for low income families
Anglicare invests $70 million in Rooty Hill
Latest Anglicare program provides housing for families in transition
Penrith Aboriginal Community Celebrates Grandparents with Anglicare
Not enough jobs for low skilled unemployed, Anglicare reveals
Liverpool Kitchen Feeds the Homeless
Sylvania resident celebrated for 25 year service to community
Aged Care more than a career for Waterloo resident
$100 million investment into the Milperra Community
Anglicare low cost food van drives dollar further for low income families
Anglicare’s Glenhaven Green celebrates 10th Anniversary
New changes to SRSS asylum seeker support punishes people wanting to integrate and contribute to Australia
Plans to grow Northern Inland services for people in need
Sydney Housing Crisis
Illawarra Housing Crisis
Anglicare research finds Australians living alone are doing it tougher
Balmain church launches emergency collection for asylum seekers pushed off support payments
Anglicare opens new shop in Lithgow
New Residential Aged Care Home in Dapto proposed
It’s OK not to be OK during Men’s Health Week, says Anglicare Sydney
You can’t keep a good woman down: Sue Adams, Anglicare Mt Druitt Shop Volunteer
Anglicare Sydney takes over ARK Health Care Parramatta
Free chaplaincy service for older people living at home
Three new community pantries open in St George and Sutherland Shire
New community pantry opens in Yagoona
Anglicare opens new shop in Tahmoor
Living life to the fullest: Blind pianist devotes time and talent to others
New developments approved for Anglicare Oran Park
New trial: Anglicare Op Shops expand to include affordable groceries
Anglicare supports Chris’ recovery journey
New developments approved for Anglicare Oran Park
Volunteering practical care in Campbelltown
Get involved during National Op Shop Week!
Keeping families safe in Ulladulla
New community pantry opens in Lawson
New community pantry opens in Lawson
Hope for a dementia cure
Anglicare partners with NSW Government to build more affordable housing
Anglicare Woolooware Shores to expand
Still less than 1% affordable for people on low incomes despite increase in rental properties
Anglicare low cost food van to operate in the Shoalhaven
New Anavex trial for Parkinson’s Disease to open in Sydney
Greater parenting confidence and resilience from specialised service delivery model
Anglicare low cost food van to operate in Waitara
Anglicare’s Mobile Community Pantry comes to Blacktown!
Volunteering is something Gymea resident was meant to do
Anglicare to provide mental health services not covered by the NDIS in Gunnedah
Anglicare expands their services with new shops in the Illawarra and South Coast
Lalor Park Church providing love and care in hard to reach places
Anglicare to provide mental health services not covered by the NDIS in Narrabri
New Residential Aged Care Home to be built at Oran Park
Volunteering gives Hills resident something to believe in
It’s the smiles that keep Penrith resident volunteering
Help is only a call away thanks to Illawarra volunteers like Andrew
Grandmothers give the best advice
Sussex Inlet resident provides a helping hand during times of disaster
105-year-old Castle Hill dancing queen
Anglicare provides physiotherapy with NDIS counselling packages in Moree
Anglicare helps people recognise domestic abuse
Anglicare welcomes South Korean delegation to share and learn about aged care
Anglicare to build more affordable housing in Nowra
Anglicare’s response to “catastrophic” fire forecast
Anglicare to build more affordable housing in Botany
COVID-19: Press Release from Anglicare Sydney - 23 April 2020
Anglicare volunteers upcycle for good
COVID-19: Press Release from Anglicare Sydney - 23 April 2020
Anglicare celebrates 30 years of the Lord Mayor’s Giving Tree and Bikers Run
COVID-19: Press Release from Anglicare Sydney - 24 April 2020
Anglicare says NO to domestic violence
COVID-19: Press Release from Anglicare Sydney - 24 April 2020
Anglicare brings the joy of Christmas to thousands of families
COVID-19: Press Release from Anglicare Sydney - 25 April 2020
New life at Anglicare’s Farrer Brown Court
Castle Hill dental practice winners at HESTA Aged Care Awards
Anglicare to build more housing in Fairfield
Anglicare celebrates 11 years of Aboriginal Cultural Program
Data breach notification
Someone posing as an Anglicare volunteer in Albury and Holbrook regions
Anglicare to host an affordable Wills Day in Mt Druitt
Data breach notification
COVID-19: What Anglicare is doing to protect residents, clients, staff and volunteers
Affordable food comes to Bomaderry
Strengthen your memory and boost your confidence with Brain Training
A new emotional wellbeing for older persons service provides much-needed mental health support
Thieves posing as carers and cleaners targeting elderly citizens
COVID-19: Statement from Anglicare Sydney - 29 April 2020
Severe rent stress eased by COVID-19 income support; urgent longer-term increase to payments needed
COVID-19: Media update from Anglicare Sydney - 30 April 2020
COVID-19: Media update from Anglicare Sydney - 1 May 2020
COVID-19: Media update from Anglicare Sydney - 2 May 2020
COVID-19: Supporting Families and Friends of Newmarch House - 3 May 2020
Tips to reduce your risk of dementia
Respite: Defining the care service and identifying when you need it
3 wellbeing benefits of retirement village living
Is it time for your loved one to consider aged care services ?
Rhythm of Life: A person-centred approach to aged care
Eat right to stay upright
What is residential aged care and when should we consider it?
What are the different services available for older Australians living at home ?
How to discuss residential aged care with your parents
Rental Affordability Snapshot: High rents are leaving people on low incomes out in the cold
How do you become a foster carer with Anglicare?
Three tips when choosing a home care provider
Common signs of anxiety and how you can get help
What are the different costs of residential aged care?
Demystifying home care package fees
Op Shopping: Five reasons why it's so good
4 signs of teenage depression and NSW services that can help
Speak up, open up: How we grow through personal counselling
7 tips to help you make the most of your retirement lifestyle
Grandparenting: An experience to treasure
Why it's important you continue lifelong learning into retirement
Settling Your Mind
8 things you might be thinking about Coronavirus and some ideas that could help
Back
Mr Greg Hammond OAM (Chairman)
Our home care services
How do I access home care?
What will it cost?
Why Anglicare at home?
Respite and Social Centres
Who will provide my care?
Client stories
Frequently Asked Questions
Are you caring for someone?
Mental Health Community Living Supports for Refugees
Emotional Wellbeing for Older Persons (EWOP)
Back
Learning English (ESL)
Protecting Your Privacy
Anglicare provides a range of services and collects personal information to ensure a holistic approach to the care we offer. We recognise and respect every person’s right to privacy, dignity and confidentiality.
We will:
Provide environments that enable residents & clients to maintain relationships with privacy and dignity.
Promote respectful relationships between all staff, residents, clients and their representatives.
Ensure compliance with the Privacy Act 1988 (The Act) and the 13 Australian Privacy Principles (APPs) outlined in the Act
Be open about how we manage your personal information.
If you ask us, we can give you more information about how we protect your privacy
Your Personal Information
We collect a variety of personal information so we can provide services and holistic care to our clients. Examples of personal information which we regularly collect include a person’s:
name;
contact details;
date of birth;
marital status;
family details, including personal information about an individual’s next of kin;
health and medical details
Medicare number
financial details
Sometimes we will ask you for other information depending on the type of service you would like to access from Anglicare
Collecting and Storing Information
When you contact Anglicare to access our services we will ask you questions about yourself so we can provide support that meets your needs and preferences.
We prefer to collect personal information directly from the person it relates to, however, in some cases this may be impracticable, or the information might be held by someone else.
This could include:
medical records held by your current or previous health care provider;
financial records held by an accountant or Centrelink; or
next of kin details.
You do not have to provide us with all the information we ask for, however it might limit the types of services we can offer you.
We store your information in several secure forms. These include:
paper records stored in secure cabinets and buildings
paper records that we are required to keep for legal reasons archived in secure storage
online data bases where data is entered and stored securely and access is restricted within Anglicare to those who need to access the information in providing service to you
Anonymity or Pseudonymity
You can enquire about our services anonymously or by use of a pseudonym. We will be able to discuss services that might be suitable, including costs which might be charged for those services. However, we cannot provide services to someone without confirming their identity. Until we have sufficient information to provide a detailed quote or outline of suitable services we can only give general, non – binding information.
How we use your information
Generally, we will use your information to:
assess your eligibility to access our services
adjust services to meet your specific needs
determine if you need to make any payments
contact you to discuss the services you are using and give you the opportunity to tell us what you think about your experience with Anglicare
discuss the services you are using with your family or next of kin, provided you have given us consent to do so
We may also use your information for a secondary purpose such as research or marketing if:
you have consented, or
where it is impracticable to seek consent, we will give you the opportunity to opt out of further communications.
There are also limited, serious circumstances where we will disclose personal information to third parties without your consent:
where we reasonably believe it is necessary to reduce or prevent a threat to a person’s life, health or safety or a serious threat to public health or safety;
where the use or disclosure is required by law;
where we reasonably believe that the use is necessary for law enforcement, public revenue protection, preventing or remedying of serious improper conduct, or conduct of court or tribunal proceedings, either by or on behalf of an enforcement body.
If we use or disclose information without consent we will record each instance in writing
Data Processing
Anglicare uses third party systems to process some of the data we collect, including some providers that are based outside of Australia. In all instances we ensure the contractor has appropriate controls in place to comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act and our Privacy Policy.
Accessing and Correcting Personal Information
If you ask us we can normally give you access to your personal information. However, we may deny a request for access if:
The information poses a serious threat to the life or health of any person.
Releasing information would impact upon another person’s privacy
The information relates to existing legal proceedings
Providing access would be unlawful.
The information relates to a sensitive decision about how we operate our business
If you would like to access or change your information, you can contact Anglicare. It will be necessary for you to verify your identity, and you may need to visit an Anglicare site to access the information you would like to see.
In cases where we need to access old or particularly large amounts of information we may need to charge you a small fee for the time it takes to retrieve the records.
If we do not give you access to your information, we will explain why.
Data Security
We will implement measures to protect your personal information from misuse, loss, unauthorised access, change or disclosure.
We will destroy or permanently de-identify personal information when we no longer need it or it is no longer required to be kept for legal purposes.
We will protect the security of your information during transmission by using software that encrypts information that you input
Data Breaches
The Privacy Amendment (Notifiable Data Breaches) Act 2017 requires us to let you know if your information is impacted by a data breach. This means we will let you know in the way we normally communicate with you, if:
There is unauthorised access to or disclosure of your information; or your information is lost and unauthorised access or disclosure is likely to occur; and
There is a reasonable chance that this could cause you serious harm (which can include physical, physiological, emotional, economic or reputational harm); and
We have been unable to remedy the situation in line with the Act.
If we are unable to contact any affected parties individually we will post a notification that an eligible data breach has occurred on our website.
In such circumstances we are also required to inform the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner.
We will follow our Notifiable Data Breach Procedure in these instances.
Identifiers
We will not adopt Commonwealth Government identifiers for use as our own identifiers. If we are required to collect a government identifier to provide you a service, we will not use this number to identify you in our systems.
Sensitive Information
Generally, we will only collect sensitive information with an individual’s consent, except where:
The collection is required or authorised by law or to establish, exercise or defend a legal or equitable claim, or;
It is necessary to prevent or lessen a serious or imminent threat to the life or health of the person who is the subject of the information.
Sensitive information includes things like your ethnicity, your religious beliefs, if you have a criminal record or information about your health. A full definition of sensitive information is included in the Privacy Act 1988
Donations
Anglicare gathers and retains personal information from donors which is managed in compliance with the Payment Card Industry Security Data Standard.
Donation processing is secured by encryption or masking to protect the transfer of personal and financial information. Each donation is secured, and credit card details are not stored by Anglicare. The only information collected and retained is the amount donated, transaction date and contact details as completed on the donation form
Where donations are made over the phone or via email, a copy of that donation is retained for tax and audit purposes in a secure location.
Complaints
We value your feedback on how we have treated your personal information. If you are not happy about how we protected your privacy, please contact the Privacy Officer:
Phone: 9895 8091
Email: privacy@anglicare.org.au
It is helpful if you can tell us:
How you think your information might have been misused,
The details of any of our employees involved.
The Privacy Officer might ask for extra information to help them understand your circumstances and act to resolve the issue. We will keep you updated on how we are addressing your complaint
If you aren’t happy with how we have dealt with your complaint you can ask for it to be referred to mediation. If you are still unhappy you can refer your complaint to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner.
Website Privacy
IP Addresses
Our web servers gather your IP address to assist with the diagnosis of problems with our services. This information cannot be traced to an individual user.
Cookies and Applets
This website uses Google Analytics to help analyse how people use our site. The tool uses "cookies" to collect standard internet log and visitor behaviour information in an anonymous form. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including IP address) is transmitted to Google. This information is then used to compile statistical reports on website activity for Anglicare.
We will never use the statistical analytics tool to track or to collect any Personally Identifiable Information (PII) of visitors to our site. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. Neither we nor Google will link, or seek to link, an IP address with the identity of a computer user. We will not associate any data gathered from this site with any Personally Identifiable Information from any source, unless you explicitly submit that information via a fill-in form on our website.
Links to other sites
On our website, we provide links to third party Web sites. These linked sites are not under our control, and we cannot accept responsibility for the conduct of companies linked to our website. Before disclosing your personal information on any other website, we advise you to examine the terms and conditions of using that Web site and its privacy statement.
Personal Information
Personal information about visitors to our site is collected only when knowingly and voluntarily submitted. For example, we may need to collect such information to provide you with further services or to answer or forward any requests or enquiries. Copies of correspondence sent from the web site, that may contain personal information, are stored as archives for record-keeping and back-up purposes only.
Credit Card Details
We ensure that payment card information is kept confidential and secure, and that there is compliance with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard.
Security
We strive to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of personal information submitted to our website, and we regularly review and update our security measures.
We will take all reasonable steps to protect any personal information you transmit to us online. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be totally secure, and there is an inherent risk in using this channel that you should be aware of.
Our employees and the contractors who provide services related to our information systems are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by us. However, we will not be held responsible for events arising from unauthorised access to your personal information.
Moderation guidelines for Anglicare Sydney’s social media pages
Anglicare Sydney supports Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, LinkedIn, YouTube, Snapchat and Google+ terms of use and related policies and asks other social media users to do the same.
In order to ensure Anglicare Sydney’s social media pages remain friendly, informative and welcoming for all visitors, we do moderate pages when needed.
Anglicare Sydney encourages discussion and opinion sharing via Anglicare Sydney’s social media pages, however, spam content will be removed. Spam content includes, but is not limited to unrelated information, excessively posting large quantities of questions after an answer has been provided, business promotion or promotion of another page, and comments that are defamatory, contain hate speech, false and misleading, infringe on copyright, offensive, abusive, harassing, or threatening.
We ask that when contributing your views to Anglicare Sydney’s social media pages, you ensure that you:
Do not harass, abuse, threaten or discriminate against other social media users including Anglicare Sydney's employees
Do not post items that are likely to offend others
Do not use obscene, offensive or inappropriate language
Do not post repeat comments continuously
Do not post or tag Anglicare Sydney excessively as this impedes the ability for others to utilise the selected page to communicate with Anglicare Sydney
Do not promote commercial interests, advertisements or endorsements of anything that is not related to Anglicare Sydney
Protect the personal privacy of your own and others by not publicly posting personal information, such as names, email addresses, phone numbers and home addresses on the Anglicare Sydney's social media pages
Respect and kindly consider Anglicare Sydney’s Vision, Mission and Values when interacting with the page
Failing to adhere to the above guidelines will result in moderation and potential banning from our pages, untagging of the Anglicare Sydney's name and removal of posts from Anglicare Sydney's social media pages.
